Many organizations have moved from hardwired server rooms to operations that are
run by cloud based facilities because it provides both security and flexibility.
Cloud service providers have different availability zones so that
if one goes down activities can shift to another,
you don't have to maintain a whole data center with
all the redundancy that entails the cloud service provider.
Does that for you?
There are several ways to contract with a cloud service provider.
You can set up the billing so that it
depends on the data used just like your mobile phone
and you have resource pooling,
meaning you can share in the resources of other colleagues or similar
types of industries to provide data for artificial intelligence or analytic.